EDWIN HU

a: (202) 551-8993

Securities and Exchange Commission Last Updated: 2019-11-19

100 F St NE

Washington, D.C. 20549 ⊠: hue@sec.gov ♦: edwinhu.github.io

RESEARCH AND INTERESTS

My current research is focused on market structure issues including competition between financial institutions—e.g., banks and exchanges—and the effects on market quality. My policy work is focused on identifying gaps in securities laws, which often intersect with issues in corporate and fiduciary law, and developing solutions to the resulting agency problems.

EMPLOYMENT

2018—Present: Counsel to Commissioner Robert J. Jackson Jr. Securities and Exchange Commission, Washington, D.C.

- Chief economic advisor with primary responsibility for development, coordination, and production of economic analyses including original research that has been cited in legislation and most major media outlets.
- Principal policy advisor on trading and markets and economic and risk analysis issues. Advisor
 on investment management, corporate finance, and accounting issues.
- Determine and execute communications strategy, with success obtaining features on television, print, blogs, and podcasts. Responsible for legislative affairs—including technical assistance on bills and hearings.
- Develop and write speeches, statements, and op-eds that have appeared in *The New York Times* and *The Wall Street Journal*.

2016–2018: Financial Economist Fellow

Securities and Exchange Commission, Washington, D.C.

Division of Economic and Risk Analysis

- Development and production of original economic research on controversial issues in financial markets.
- My research showing that 'speed bumps' may improve market quality was featured in *The Wall Street Journal*.

EDUCATION

2010–2016 Rice University

• Ph.D, M.A. Finance. Jones Graduate School of Business.

2006–2010 University of Washington

- B.S. Applied and Computational Mathematical Sciences.
- B.S. Economics Cum Laude.

Loan Syndication Networks with Jeffrey Harris, and Ioannis Spyridiopoulos

• Presented at FMA (2019*)

Banks develop network connections through repeated co-syndication relationships with multiple lenders. We create measures of network centrality based on banks' historical co-syndication ties, and find that well-connected lenders are more likely to gain lead underwriter status and offer better loan terms. Our results are robust to variation in network connections generated by bank consolidations. Well-connected banks offer lower spreads to firms with higher levels of information asymmetry, underwrite loans faster, and retain a smaller fraction of the loan. The evidence is more consistent with recent theory suggesting networks mitigate information asymmetry in syndicates, rather than superior screening or monitoring.

Intentional Access Delays, Market Quality, and Price Discovery: Evidence from IEX Becoming an Exchange

- Covered in the Wall Street Journal (1) (2), Globe and Mail, Traders Magazine, TabbFORUM, Financial Times, Fast Company (Video)
- Presented at Securities and Exchange Commission (2019), DC Juniors Finance Conference (2019)

This paper exploits cross-sectional variation in trading activity and the staggered securities phase-in when the Investors Exchange (IEX) becomes a national securities exchange to study the effects of intentional access delays on market quality and price discovery. Market quality improves after IEX becomes an exchange for securities with high historical IEX market share. Price discovery improves overall, although IEX's contribution to price discovery remains small. Intermarket Sweep Order activity decreases overall, coinciding with improvements in price discovery. In a second natural experiment where IEX's ECN goes dark in 28 symbols there is no change in market quality or price discovery. The findings in this paper suggest that protected markets with symmetric speed bumps may be a feasible solution to deemphasize speed in lieu of regulatory intervention.

A comparison of some structural models of private information arrival with Jefferson Duarte, and Lance Young

- Forthcoming in Journal of Financial Economics
- Presented at Rice University (2015), Texas A&M (2015*), Multinational Finance Society Conference (MFS, 2015*) **Best Paper Award**, China International Finance Conference (CICF, 2015*), Society of Financial Econometrics Conference (SoFiE, 2015*), Instituto Technologico Autonomo de Mexico Conference (ITAM, 2015*), American Finance Association Conference (AFA, 2016), University of Washington (2016*), University of Virginia (McIntire) (2017*), Southern Methodist University (2017*).
- Data and Previous Refereed Versions
- Previously circulated under: "Does the PIN Model Mis-Identify Private Information and If So, What is the Alternative?"

We show that the PIN and the Duarte and Young (2009) (APIN) models do not match the variability of noise trade in the data and that this limitation has severe implications for how

these models identify private information. We examine two alternatives to these models, the Generalized PIN model (GPIN) and the Odders-White and Ready (2008) model (OWR). Our tests indicate that measures of private information based on the OWR and GPIN models are promising alternatives to the APIN's Adj.PIN and PIN

Financial Integration and Credit Democratization: Linking Banking Deregulation to Economic Growth with Elizabeth Berger, Alexander Butler, and Morad Zekhnini

- Revise and Resubmit Journal of Financial Intermediation
- Presented at Rice University (2012*), Financial Management Association Conference (FMA 2013), Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC, 2014*), Fordham University (2014*), University of Cincinnati (2014*), University of Kentucky (2014*), Yale School of Management (2015*).

We document a positive effect of financial integration on economic growth. Using US state-by-state financial deregulations, we find that economic growth occurred in states where bank deregulation solved a capital immobility problem. We use a matching method that constructs synthetic counterfactual states to identify the channels that link bank deregulation to financial integration, and thereby to economic growth. Our results reveal a correlation between financial integration and subsequent banking sector changes including improved bank efficiency, better lending and borrowing rates, and an expansion in loan recipients. We show that financial integration democratizes lending and spurs economic growth.

Policy Work

I worked on policy issues including M&A disclosures, margin requirements for security futures, human capital disclosures, executive hedging disclosures, the Transaction Fee Pilot, and the Volcker Rule. I also conducted original policy research summarized below:

Proposed Rules Governing Proxy Advisors and Shareholder Proposals

- Conducted research showing how the proposed rules would affect the resubmission of share-holder proposals, and the effect of including shareholder proposals on firm value (see Data Appendix).
- Received support from Chair Waters and Ranking Member Brown.
- Selected coverage: CNBC, Politico, Bloomberg (Money Stuff), Recode Decode (Podcast)
- Featured: Harvard Law School Forum on Corporate Governance and Financial Regulation, Chicago Booth Stigler Center ProMarket Blog

Rules Governing Investment Advice (Regulation Best Interest)

- Conducted research showing that the proposed interpretation of the fiduciary standard was related to higher rates of conflicted advice.
- Received support from prominent legislators including Senators Warren, Booker, Speaker Pelosi, Chair Waters, and a dozen bipartisan securities law professors.
- House Passed Amendment 78 to H.R. 3351 over concerns from Chair Maxine Waters about lowering the fiduciary standard.
- Selected coverage: Washington Post, New York Times, Wall Street Journal, Bloomberg, Money Stuff

Amendments to Sarbanes-Oxley 404(b) Accelerated Filer Definition

- Conducted research on the costs and benefits of rolling back auditor attestation requirements for smaller firms.
- Received support from dozens of law and accounting faculty.
- Selected coverage: Wall Street Journal

Stock Buybacks and Corporate Cashouts

- Conducted research showing that the market reacts negatively to insider selling after stock buyback announcements in reponse to a letter from Senator Chris Van Hollen.
- Letter, Data Appendix
- Cited in leglisation proposed by Senator Tammy Baldwin, and Petition to SEC
- Selected coverage: CNN, Washington Post, CNBC, Fox Business, The Atlantic

Bats Market Close: Off-Exchange Closing Volume and Price Discovery

- First SEC economic analysis to use regulatory audit trail and TRF data.
- Led to NYSE cutting its top tier MOC fees by two-thirds.
- Selected coverage: Wall Street Journal

Tick Size Pilot Program and Market Quality with Paul Hughes, John Ritter, Patti Vegella, and Hao Zhang

• We find evidence that market quality deteriorates after the Tick Size Pilot widens quoting increments to five cent increments.

SKILLS

Data analysis, financial econometrics, high performance scientific computing, parallel computing, data visualization, causal inference, matching.

python, R, SAS, stata, sql, bash, git, awk, latex